export const quizQuestions = [
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "On which date is the International Day of Women and Girls in Science celebrated globally?",
    options: ["March 8", "October 15", "December 10", "February 11"],
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "Who was the first person to win Nobel Prizes in two different scientific fields (Physics and Chemistry)?",
    options: [
      "Dorothy Hodgkin",
      "Marie Curie",
      "Ada Lovelace",
      "Rosalind Franklin",
    ],
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question:
      "Known as the 'Missile Woman of India', who was the Project Director for the Agni-IV missile?",
    options: [
      "Ritu Karidhal",
      "Kalpana Chawla",
      "Muthayya Vanitha",
      "Tessy Thomas",
    ],
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "Which English mathematician is widely considered to be the first computer programmer?",
    options: [
      "Mary Jackson",
      "Grace Hopper",
      "Katherine Johnson",
      "Ada Lovelace",
    ],
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question:
      "Rosalind Franklin's 'Photo 51' was critical to the discovery of the double helix structure of which molecule?",
    options: ["Insulin", "Hemoglobin", "DNA", "Penicillin"],
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question: "Who was the first woman of Indian origin to go to space?",
    options: [
      "Sirisha Bandla",
      "Kalpana Chawla",
      "Shawna Pandya",
      "Sunita Williams",
    ],
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question:
      "Jane Goodall is a world-renowned primatologist best known for her long-term study of which animals?",
    options: ["Orangutans", "Lemurs", "Chimpanzees", "Gorillas"],
    answer: 2,
  },
  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      "Which Janaki Ammal is a renowned Indian scientist in which field?",
    options: ["Nuclear Physics", "Botany", "Oceanography", "Astrophysics"],
    answer: 1,
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      "The movie 'Hidden Figures' celebrates the contributions of Katherine Johnson, Dorothy Vaughan, and Mary Jackson to which organization?",
    options: ["CERN", "ISRO", "SpaceX", "NASA"],
    answer: 3,
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      "Who was the first woman to win the Fields Medal, often described as the 'Nobel Prize of Mathematics'?",
    options: [
      "Maryam Mirzakhani",
      "Emmy Noether",
      "Hypatia",
      "Sophie Germain",
    ],
    answer: 0,
  },
];
